{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. The Kinetic energy of an object of mass 1 Kg is 72 J. The momentum of the object is:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "6 Kg m/s",
        "b": "12 Kg m/s",
        "c": "9 Kg m/s",
        "d": "24 Kg m/s"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Impulse is defined as the change in:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Kinetic energy",
        "b": "Linear momentum",
        "c": "Linear velocity",
        "d": "Acceleration"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. What is the momentum of an object having mass of 14 Kg and velocity 28 m/s?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "1/392 kg-m/s",
        "b": "2 Kg-m/s",
        "c": "0.5 Kg-m/s",
        "d": "392 Kg-m/s"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Two balls at the same temperature collide. What is conserved?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Momentum",
        "b": "Velocity",
        "c": "Temperature",
        "d": "Kinetic Energy"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },{
      "question": "5. If the linear momentum of a moving object gets doubled due to application of a force, then its kinetic energy will",
      "answers":{
        "a":"remain same",
        "b":"to increase by four times",
        "c": "to increase by two times",
        "d": "to increase by eight times"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"6. which of the energy is possessed by a horse running on a level road?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Potential energy",
        "b": "Kinetic energy",
        "c": "pressure energy",
        "d":"heat energy"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"7. When the speed of a moving body is doubled?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "its acceleration is doubled",
        "b": "its momentum is doubled",
        "c":"its kinetic energy is doubled",
        "d":"its potential energy is doubled"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. What would be the momentum of the bullet and the gun before firing?",
      "answers":{
        "a":"the momentum of the bullet and the gun before firing would be zero",
        "b": "the momentum of the bullet would be more than that of the gun",
        "c":"the momentum of the gun would be more than that of the bullet",
        "d": "both would have certain velocity and so have the same momentum"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"9. If the momentum of an object increases by 20%, its kinetic energy will increase by________.",
      "answers":{
        "a":"66%",
        "b":"77%",
        "c":"44%",
        "d":"55%"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"c",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
      
    },{
      "question":"10. Find the momentum of a body of mass 200g having a kinetic energy of 10J.",
      "answers":{
        "a":"20 kgm/s",
        "b":"0.2 kgm/s",
        "c": "2 kgm/s",
        "d": "2000 kgm/s"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"c",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    }
  ]
}